Jensen, Vernon H. Additional Arbitration Files 5902
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Vernon H. Jensen Additional Arbitration Files
1951-1984
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Jensen, Vernon H.
5902
4 cubic feet
4 linear ft.
Records (documents).
5731614
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 21, 2005
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 17, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Vernon Jensen (July 10, 1907 - September 27, 1998) was a founding faculty member of Cornell's New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
A graduate of Brigham Young University (BS '32), Jensen worked as a substitute teacher in Salt Lake City after college before leaving to pursue graduate study at the University of California at Berkeley (PhD '39). Shortly before completing his degree, Jensen began teaching at the University of Colorado. He taught at UC from 1937 to 1946, during which time he also served as a consultant to the National Defense Mediation Board (1941) and a public panel member, mediator and arbitrator for the National War Labor Board (1942) and Wage Stabilization Director of the NWLB's Ninth Region (1942-1944).
Jensen was among the founding faculty of the School of Industrial and Labor Relations, joining Cornell in 1946. Jensen became Associate Dean of the ILR School in 1965 and was elected to Cornell's Board of Trustees in 1973. In addition to numerous articles, Jensen wrote four books, Lumber and Labor (1945), Heritage of Conflict (1950), Collective Bargaining in the Nonferrous Metal Industry (1955), and Hiring of Dockworkers and Employment Practices in the Ports of New York, London, Liverpool, Rotterdam, and Marseilles (1964).
See the Cornell University Faculty Memorial Statement for Professor Vernon Jensen: http://hdl.handle.net/1813/18668
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3002: Vernon H. Jensen Papers /4007: Vernon H. Jensen Additional Records /4067: Vernon H. Jensen Longshore Research Files /4096: Vernon H. Jensen Additional Research and Office Files /4128: Vernon H. Jensen Additional Papers /4128 AV: Vernon H. Jensen Audio-Visual Materials /4137: Vernon H. Jensen Additional Files 5739: Post Office Arbitration Files 5839: Vernon Jenson Additional Arbitration Files
Collective bargaining.; Temporary employees.; Employees -- Suspension; Senority, Employee; Machinists; Automobile industry and trade; Chemical industry -- Employees; Metal trade; Metal workers -- Labor unions; Textile industry; Textile workers -- Labor unions; Communication and traffic; Electricians -- Labor unions; Arbitration, Industrial; Absenteeism (Labor); Discrimination in employment; Grievance arbitration; Insubordination; Jensen, Vernon H.; Allied Chemical Corporation. Industrial Chemical Division.; United Steelworkers of America. Local 12457; Allied Chemical Corporation. Specialty Chemical Division.; United Steelworkers of America. Local 593 (Buffalo, N.Y.); Anaconda American Brass Company; Bell Aerosystems Company.; International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Local 501 (Buffalo, N.Y.); Columbian Rope Company; Textile Workers Union of America; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; Curtiss-Wright Corporation.; United Steelworkers of America. Local 4533; Dollinger Corporation.; International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers. Local 329 (Rochester, N.Y.); Dresser Mfg.; International Association of Machinists and Atomic Workers. Lodge 1965 (Wellsboro, Pa.); Dresser Mfg. Transportation Equipment Division.; United Steelworkers of America. Local 1630 (Depew, N.Y.); General Aniline & Film Corporation; Great Atlantic & Pacific Tea Company; Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America.; Houdaile Industries; United Steelworkers of America. Local 4533 (Buffalo, N.Y.)
5731614
- Acme Markets, Inc., 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alco Engine Division, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Allied Chemical vs. Industrial Steelworkers of America, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Allied Chemical vs. Industrial Steelworkers of America #2, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Allied Chemical Corporation vs. International Union District 50, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Allied Chemical vs. United Steelworkers of America #3, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- American LaFrance vs. International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- American LaFrance vs. International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- American-Standard Inc., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- American-Standard vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- American-Standard vs. United Steelworkers of America #2, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- American Sterilizer Company vs. International Association of Machinists & Atomic Workers, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Anaconda American Brass Company vs. Buffalo Brass and Copper Workers Union, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Anaconda American Brass Company vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- The Anaconda Company, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Vernon H. Jensen, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Ashland Oil Company vs. Independent Oil Workers Union, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Independent Oil Workers, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- AVCO vs. United Automobile Workers, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- AVCO, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Bell Aerosystems Company vs. Niagara Frontier Technical Division, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Bell Aerosystems Company vs. UAW, 1951-1956 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Union brief on Grievances 70-193, 70-471 and 70-613, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Bell Aerosystems Company vs. UAW, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Bell Aerospace Company vs. UAW, 1953-1973 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Bennett-Ireland Inc., 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- City of Binghamton vs. AFSCME, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- American Arbitration Association, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Borden Inc. vs. Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of America, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Vernon H. Jensen Misc. Documents, 1962-1972 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Borden Chemical vs. International Association of Machinists, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Buxton Inc. vs. International Leather Goods, Plastic and Novelty, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Interstate United Corporation vs. UAW, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Cellu Products, Inc. vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- American Arbitration Association, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Central School District; Towns of Salina and Clay Liverpool vs. AFL-CIO, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Letters to Vernon H. Jensen, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Letters to Vernon H. Jensen #2, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Textile Workers Union of America vs. Columbian Rope Company, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Columbian Rope Company vs. Textile Workers Union of America, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Columbian Rope Company vs. Textile Workers Union of America #2, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Columbian Rope Company vs. Textile Workers Union of America #3, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Columbian Rope Company vs. Textile Workers Union of America #4, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Columbian Rope Company vs. Textile Workers Union of America #5, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Boston Electrotypers Unions vs. Courier-Citizen Company, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Curbell Inc., 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Textile Workers Union of America AFL-CIO vs. Curbell Inc., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Curbell Inc. #2, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Curtiss-Wright Corporation vs. International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers vs Office and Professional Employees International Union, 1967- 1968 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Curtiss-Wright Corporation vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Notes, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Curtiss-Wright corporation vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Curtiss-Wright Corporation vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Curtiss-Wright Corporation vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Curtiss-Wright Corporation vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Curtiss-Wright Corporation vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Curtiss-Wright Corporation vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Curtiss-Wright Corporation vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Curtiss-Wright Corporation vs. United Steelworkers of America, Hearings 1969 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Curtiss-Wright Corporation vs. United steelworkers of America, Hearings 1970 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- International Brotherhood of Pulp. Sulphite and Papermill Workers Union vs. United Merchants and Manufacturers Inc., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Dairylea Cooperative, Inc. vs. Milk Drivers and Dairy Employees, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Vernon H. Jensen Arbitration Letters, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- DeLaval Turbine Inc. vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- DeLaval Turbine Inc., 1965-1968 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Dollinger vs. IUE-AFL-CIO, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Dollinger Corporation vs. AFL-CIO, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Dollinger Corporation vs. AFL-CIO, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Vernon H. Jensen; Arbitration between Dollinger Corporation and IUE Local No. 329, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- IUE and Dollinger Corporation, Letters, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Final Filters, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- General Analine and film Corporation vs. Local 306, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Flame Cut Parts, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Tow Motor Maintenance, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Compression Fitting Plant vs. International Association of Machinists, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Compressing Fitting Plant vs. International Association of Machinists & Aerospace Workers, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Compression Fitting Plant vs. IAMAW, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Compression Fitting Plant vs. IAMAW, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Dresser Industries Inc. vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Dresser Industries vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Dresser Industries Inc. vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- United Teachers Association No. 2626 vs. Dunkirk City School District, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Hooker Chemicals vs. AFL-CIO, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Eltra Corporation vs. Local 621, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Eltra Corporation vs. Local No. 621, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Wholesale Grocery Co. vs. Local 338, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- County of Erie and Erie Community College vs. Faculty of Erie Community College, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Erie Community College Arbitration, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Evans Chemetics, Incorporated vs. Local Union 7110, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Arbitrator's Notes, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Faberge Incorporated, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Fairport Education Association vs. Fairport School District, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Frontier Oil Mining Company vs. Independent Oil Workers Union, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Frontier Oil Mining Company vs. Independent Oils Workers Union, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Independent Oil Workers Union and Ashland Oil Refinery, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- General Analine and Film Corporation vs. Local 306, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- General Analine and Film Corporation vs. Local 306, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- General Analine and Film Corporation vs. Local 306, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- General Analine and Film Corporation vs. Lodge 1807 of the IAMAW, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- General Analine and Film Corporation vs. Local 71-71a, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- General Aniline and Film Corporation vs. Local 277, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- General Dynamics vs. Local No. 1 RIWU, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- General Dynamics, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- General Dynamics vs. RIWU Local no. 1, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- General Electric Company vs. International Association of Machinists Lodge No. 157, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- General Electric Company vs. International Association of Machinist Lodge No. 157, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- General Fiber Box Company vs. Printing Specialties and Paper Products Union, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Gould-National Batteries Inc. vs. United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- The Great Atlantic and Pacific Tea Company vs. American Baking and Confectionary Workers International Union, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- The Great Atlantic and Pacific Tea Company vs. Cannery and Manufacturing Employees, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- The Great A & P Tea Company vs. Cannery and Manufacturing Plant Employees, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- The Great A & P Tea Company vs. Cannery and Manufacturing Plant Employees, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- The Great A & P Tea Company vs. Cannery and Manufacturing Plant Employees, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Hotel Restaurants and Bartenders Union, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Hard Manufacturing Company vs. United Automobile Workers Union, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Hospital Service Plan of New Jersey vs. Office Employees International Union, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Houdaille Industries, Inc. vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Houdaille Industries Inc. vs. United Steelworkers, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Houdaille Industries vs. International Association of Machinists and aerospace Workers, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Houdaille Industries Inc. vs. International Association of Machinists, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Imperial Paper Company vs. United Paperworkers International Union, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Imperial Wallpaper Mill, Inc. vs. United Paperworkers International Union, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Ingersoll-Rand Company vs. International Association of Machinists, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- The International Nickel Company, Inc. vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- UMWA vs. International Salt Company, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Jones & Laughlin Steel Company vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Kennedy Valve Mfg. Co., Inc. vs. United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Koppers Pittsburgh Company vs. United Mine Workers of America, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Koppers Company inc. vs. Oil, Chemical and Atomic Workers Union, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Louis Marx company vs. IAMAW, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Melrose Trading Corporation vs. Retail store Employees Union, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Modine Manufacturing Company vs. International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- The Monarch Machine Tool Company vs. United Automobile Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- County of Monroe vs. Security and Law Enforcement, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Monsdanto chemical company vs. Monsanto Industrial Union, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- New York State Thruway Employees Union vs. NYS Thruway Authority, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Strong Memorial Hospital vs. National Union of Hospital and Health care Employees, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Strong Memorial Hospital, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- University of Rochester Arbitration, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Investigation of Dispute Between Strong Memorial Hospital and National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Hospital Position on Issues, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- WNY Hospital Agreements, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- WNY hospital Agreements Folder #2, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- WNY Hospital Agreement Folder #3, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- 3 M Company vs. IAM, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Webster Central School District vs. The Webster Teachers Association, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Webster Central School District vs. Webster Teachers Association, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- William Cholson and Co., Inc. vs. Amalgamated Jewelry, Diamond and Watchbase Workers Union, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Amalgamated Jewelry, Diamond and Watchbase Workers Union, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Arbitrator's Bills and Notes, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Vernon H. Jensen; Finances, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Vernon H. Jensen; Finances #2, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Misc. Agreement Books, 1965-1984 (Box 4, Folder 47)